Guide to the Robert E. Swain Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert E. Swain papers
1916-1938
SC0039
Swain, Robert E. (Robert Eccles), 1875-1961.
1 Linear feet
Correspondence between Dr. Swain and Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur regarding the Chemistry Department and records pertaining to the honor system in the Chemistry Department (1916-1920) and the Cardinal Gun Club (1928-1930).
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, Chemistry Department, 1968.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Chemistry at Stanford (1902-1941; emeritus 1941-1961), head of the Chemistry Department (1917-1941) and acting president of Stanford (1929-1933). Prof. Swain died in 1961.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence between Dr. Swain and Stanford President Ray Lyman Wilbur regarding the Chemistry Department and records pertaining to the honor system in the Chemistry Department (1916-1920) and the Cardinal Gun Club (1928-1930).
Access Terms
Stanford University. Cardinal Gun Club.; Stanford University. Department of Chemistry. Faculty.; Swain, Robert E. (Robert Eccles), 1875-1961.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1916-1938
  - Honor system in the Chemistry Department records, 1916-1920 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Constitution, mimeographed announcements, flyers and minutes.
  - Cardinal Gun Club, 1928-1930 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    A small group of Stanford - Palo Alto men including Dr. Swain.
  - Chemistry Department meeting in executive session, 1924-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1917-1918; 1919-1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence between R.E. Swain and R.L. Wilbur, 1925-1932; 1933-1934; 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 18)